when i rewatch these like takes a second
to start so it cuts me off mid-sentence
every time but today for the idea cafe
I'm joined by Jessica and our question
we're discussing because I cannot
remember the exact wording is how does
your sexual / romantic orientation
affect your worldview there's gonna be a
slightly different format to the World
Cafe going forward the World Cafe that's
what this is based on but the idea cafe
because I want there to be a different
format it works better to find one
person to have a conversation with we
together craft a question that we want
to discuss figure out a time that works
for us and then put it out into the
community to see who else wants to
participate so there's always at least
two of us and potentially more and it
will always be a question that I want to
talk about and the other person so I
think that this is ideal
all right so would you like to go first
Jessica answering the question then
would you like rated course yes well I
think we have a similar style in our
relationship and romantic outlook so
maybe I'm gonna steal all the good
points so yeah I'll good oh yes oh well
so we'll do that brief five minutes yeah
okay so well so I think there's two two
things about my sexuality and like
romantic life that kind of have their
own separate distinct things and then
they also have like um I like emergent
properties because they both exist for
me so I'm bisexual
and I'm polyamorous so those two things
kind of mesh well quite well to create a
kind of different worldview so I guess
the UM the bisexuality the thing that
was huge for me was having a really
strong empathy for people especially
when it comes to gender because it's
it's a really interesting time when you
have to like step outside of a role
potentially like especially if you
didn't identify as bi for a while and
then do so
you've been trying to be romantically
engaged with one gender and then you
they're not trying to be romantically
engaged with another gent so you
suddenly see what it's like from the
other side of the mirror where you're
trying to yeah you're trying to engage
in like romantic stuff with a gender
that you're not used to so you suddenly
see how hard it must be for the people
who have been trying to engage with you
as well so yes so it's kind of like an
empathy for gender roles and then once
you kind of look at gender a lot you
start seeing that the rest of the world
kind of has like gender blind spots so
one of the things that we've been joking
about in my house in the last couple of
weeks is um segregating into single
gender like toilets and changing rooms
like thinking that that eliminates any
kind of sexual pressure because the
world is hetero like ha ha ha you think
you're safe but you're not so there's a
few like gender blind spots there so
that's the buy-side and then the poly
side actually the biggest thing for me
was it was the first encounter I'd had
with their concept of abundance versus
scarcity which is interesting I think
you do see abundance around quite a lot
in in some of the circles that kind of
like so called like hippy view of the
world and this idea that you're not
sharing out a scarce resource you're
like the more you use something like the
more of the resource that you you have
or the more that you can generate so
poor emery obviously says that with love
and affection and attention so yeah I
was actually quite shocked to remember
to realize that that was the point oh he
was the first time I'd come across
abundance because I think abundance is
really important and really lovely for
like the world moving forward trying to
be in an abundant place
and I guess some subsidiary stuff from
being polyamorous is a awareness of
roles like a relationship roles as well
as gender roles so this is how this is
how it goes well together cuz you've
kind of got
Durrell's with the by stuff but then you
have like relationship roles with the
poly stuff so you suddenly realized that
if sex isn't the only way to be faithful
to someone or it's no longer the way you
show your faithfulness then what does
faithfulness mean so you sort of start
looking at like romantic life and but
and sexual life as being separate and
then maybe friendship life and also
domestic life so these are all they used
to be or bundled and now they're all
unbundled so yeah I think it I feel like
there's more granularity to life with
when you have to live in a polyamorous
way those are my yeah I think there's my
main points what about you do you Thank
You Jessica you stole it all I can't
possibly talk five minutes sexualities
all we got for the whole world that's it
I am similarly I don't even know what my
light labels are because there are
labels kind of in my head more so than
in actual reality I thought I was
straight for a very long time and when I
came out to myself I came out to the
world because I'm not someone who lives
in closet so like I was watching orange
is the new black four or five years ago
and there was this really sweet see and
I remember who was between who say I'm
sure and so and I was like oh I want to
go to prison and have a girl friends and
I was like that's not a straight thought
like I was like oh yeah girlfriend and
not go to prison right for allowing it
then and because it kind of opened up I
realized all the ways I was labeling
myself as straight because I fit in this
box and I didn't like certain things I
liked other things once that broke open
it broke open like that intertwined if
like gender and sexuality and roles in
all of exactly what you were saying yeah
I was like oh god like I had such
stringent rules on dating men that were
very rigid now I can see the very tied
to my autism which I also didn't figure
out too much later but like he's got to
be taller and he's got a lake maybe make
more money or he's got he's got to be
older and I'm like oh god what do I
there was a certain thing I was trying
to be to attract him even if it wasn't
conscious yeah he came a okay well now
here's who I'm attracted to I'm
attracted to androgynous or masculine
females and regardless of sex and like
all of these other these other
categories that work shown in the media
or I probably would have figured it out
much earlier and so okay we'll do if I
want that who do I have to be to attract
that I'm like no not doing that anymore
I want to be who I want to be and I'll
see who that attracts or I won't attract
anyone and I also I don't I think it was
maybe before I figured out I was clear
um I came across the label demisexual on
OkCupid OkCupid has all of the little
checkmark boxes to find and like
sapiosexual I haven't known what that is
before and although I find intelligence
sexy I can still find somebody sexy
without that means smart so I'm like no
not sapiosexual
but demisexual which is you have to have
an emotional connection before you're
like sexually attracted and I was like
oh that's me and when I talked to some
family members and some other people
that like well yeah but everyone is I'm
like no no they're not like they're like
well yeah well I like to be you know
emotionally connected before I have have
sex and like that's not the same thing
because if you want it but you're not
doing it because of stigma or because of
that's different I have zero attraction
zero interest until I know you and see
you as a human being and society's not
really set up for that it's set up for
like that attraction and then the
woman's both in the hetero so still like
be like oh no no this isn't okay your
sister like pursue me and it was just a
lot of breaking down of my own internal
bias and my own ideas of what life was
and so that greatly affects my role for
you cuz I'm like if I didn't know who I
am
how do I know what the hell is going on
with anything like yeah I don't and so
there's this enough thing as permanent
and everything can be questioned and I
didn't even know how much I was living
my gender because I didn't think I was I
wasn't just feminine as my sister I
wasn't as FEMEN
his women and I was fine with it but I
also was trying to be so many things and
thought I had to be something to attract
something and what you said about
abundance also definitely comes into
play I like to think on Polly but I
don't know how that would actually play
out in real life because with my health
conditions I haven't dated I have a
child of a single parent and she gets
all of my spoons and being a demisexual
there isn't necessarily I was just
watching the good doctor which is about
like an autistic doctor and he also he's
like it's not worth it to date and I'm
like yeah I get it that's totally how I
feel like there isn't enough of a bonus
for what I would have to give up and
what I would have to go through to do
that eventually it will be eventually
I'll find someone and be like oh you're
worth it you're worth it deal with all
of this stuff to all the emotions all of
whether Paul your bonaga monogamous but
within that space of abundance like I
find it so weird that our society's so
set up for monogamy where you're
supposed to be with one person generally
of the opposite sex
mm-hm and yet everything is set up
around like if there's only one you're
supposed to be with why are we so set up
for this because if you have one why do
you have to interact with everybody like
there could be or should be your sexual
partner like that we give people more an
advantage in the workplace when they
look better right like our versions of
what beauty is is like symmetry and and
like fertility we're you don't like why
when if we're only gonna be with one
person it's like it's both this scarcity
and yet you're only with one person and
so it's it's a weird sense of loss of
like abundance and and scarcity that
like I'm still definitely figuring out
how much of that and spills over into
everything that people have in
heterosexual relationships often can't
have friends that are outside of yeah
but and I'm like when I broke up with my
ex-boyfriend number one of the first I
was like you're not gonna get to be
friends with me when you're in with your
next partner he was like that's not
gonna happen I don't like I'm not that
type of person he's not that type of
person cuz he's he's a he's with someone
who's very very
to him remaining friends and but like
that was a worry I'm like I'm friends
with all my exes because I love them as
human beings or I wouldn't be with them
and I think that's also an aspect of
demo section demisexual is like also
once I've loved you I'll love you
forever because I saw essence that I
love you it's not about ownership and
it's not about needing to have you
exclusively mine it's just like yeah I
loved you and so I'm going to continue
that's just how it is
and so I've gone over my five minutes
but that was that was mine there we go
we covered it all Jessica we're done
[Laughter]
there we go abundance for all everyone's
probably know everybody sexual
congratulations everyone
I do feel like I'm a lot of people say
that it must be difficult to be
polyamorous and they say things like how
do you have the time and things like
that but I've got a few little lesser
things that make me feel different when
I put me on risk and some other make
thing like something is like life is
much easier so yeah so I've got group
sex is super easy I wouldn't know but
yeah complex to me but I guess getting
their needs met you don't feel the need
to like all of them is on you or vice
the guts that's really good
yeah well just uh just carry it to
happen I think it's difficult if you're
not Norman or Commerce and if you're not
bisexual like I mean not saying you have
to be it is possible but you end up with
people wanting to add like someone else
into their cup or say but that someone
else has to be into both of you so like
they have to be bi so we're already in
the like small pool kind of thing and
then they they have to be into you
sexually but they're not be a threat
emotionally because otherwise you know
there might be jealousy at might yeah my
threatened
the couple's relationship and stuff and
so the person has something arrived
fancy everyone have sex with them and
then like disappear into thin air and
have no might not exist anymore straight
afterwards I think so that there's no
jealousy so but I see that never ever
happens or you know rarely happens and
actually there's more wiggle room for
people who do manage to make it happen
and also nominee if it's a hatch a
couple it has to be the woman who's by
just like in it because the you know the
guy is more rarely like let's add
another man that would be fine so
there's all these like yes it's
difficult basically where is if you're
not monogamous firstly you don't have to
worry about whether you end up
developing feelings for the person that
you just had sex with because that would
be nice happened and also if you just
buy as well then yeah you can just like
stroll into a room and everyone's by and
everyone's not monogamous and just be
like hey let's have fun and there's no
like well obviously you find attractive
who you find attractive but there's a
lot of fewer barriers to like what
configuration you can do who's allowed
to do what like who is allowed to have
feelings about who it's all just so much
easier so yeah I don't know how not
bisexual and not polyamorous people ever
do anything other than like missionary
in the dark with other people though
like with other people that definitely
come like I think that's part of where
polyamory breaks down in society is that
it's generally thought of in the media
and explored in like actual reality when
there's a breakdown in a relationship so
it's like try this and I can only
imagine like like all we're really not
working let's be gay like you don't like
that's like it's like let's try being
gay that sounds like that will be make
life easier yeah one person is poly and
the other one like ok I'll try it as a
puppet like which is fair but like
it's coming from a space of because I
want to hold on to you that it's not
that's like more ownership and more and
that is not going to lead to a sense of
security and emotional stability and
emotional communication that is required
I think when you're dealing with
multiple people yeah in any relationship
whether romantic sexual combination
thereof yeah I actually tweeted the
other day that you don't see you don't
see like stable ordinary polyamorous
people in the media because it's boring
but there's no there's no drama there's
no story there's no narrative so like
even even with the best will in the
world you don't get documentaries that
are like look at all these stable and
boring people it's always the ones yeah
that have problems or they're they're
only trying it yeah as you said I did to
keep hold of their partner or to try to
fix a broken situation because yeah like
adding another person to a broken
situation definitely having a kid to fix
a relationship always works every time
time that's what we know there's so many
stories of that right like beautiful
amazing and monogamous couples that I
know who have children there is a large
percentage of them that divorced or
split up when their kids are around
three four five and those are people who
were like committed to being together
have the babies and it changed things
versus like this already isn't working
but a baby it's funny because I am a
single parent I'm a single parent by
choice and part of that is I get to see
the dynamics of like two parent one kid
families or two kids one parent and just
the difference in the diversity I'm like
I have less I don't know maybe the bit
like less ownership of my kid because
I'm her only parent so I'm like right
you can have any relationship with
anyone you want like I'm not gonna get
jealous I'm not gonna because but there
is that sense in like a triad with two
parents and a kid of like which which
would they always have their a Mama's
girl or daddy's daddy's girl right
mama's boy and it's like so you choose
one or it's like you go through a phase
with this one in a phase with that one
I'm like I'm the only one you get to go
to through phases with it there are
phases where she loves me in phases
we're on her least favorite I'm your
person like that is and I can see how
although it's not ideal for her she
wishes she especially had a dad she won
she doesn't get to exist any other way
I'm like this is the only way to you as
an entity gets to exist and I choose you
to be in existence I think the world is
a better place with you but how perfect
it is in our two-person family like I'm
like I don't think either of us would be
okay with the third person I didn't know
that before I chose to be a single
parent I was like I don't know how
anyone co-parents you feel like run
things by some videos like even if her
name I have a lot of people who are like
I was gonna need my kid back but then my
partner said no like I was like oh yeah
no I named her cuz I get to yeah and so
that's where I don't know if I could be
Polly like I can't even do the one thing
everybody else does with a partner like
single and community those are like my
two entities like in community I'm like
I'm raising my kid in community but I'm
also the one who gets to make all the
decisions so it's like I get to run
things by people but I also key I like
I'm like this is perfect me and group
and not one partner yeah that's actually
a Betty Cohen configuration pulley as
well so some people call it so low poly
where you're putting amorous in theory
and but like you that your primary
partner if you like is yourself
and actually I think that polyamory is a
way for people to explore being what
looks like more selfish so because you
can't you can't be codependent anymore
because there's not just it's not just
you and one other person like saying I
love you so much I like you know wearing
the same clothes and thinking the same
thoughts and being aligned on every
single
issue now a lot of obviously non sorry a
lot of monogamous people graduate at
that of that as well whether like look
this is my interest and these are my
projects and this is my life and it's
separate from your life but we are like
continually agreeing to have like a
coalition of two individuals that help
each other with their projects and move
forward but with polyamory you have to
be a solid like bound read individual
that knows themselves you have to like
stick up what you need and want and you
have to yeah you realize that you can't
control the thoughts and the feelings of
and the actions of other people so yeah
so I think it's very common for people
well yeah it's a thing it's where
they're like I am me and I know how I
feel and I will like negotiate how much
other people will be in my life and so
it's like to like very separate
individuals just agreeing it's a
calendar together and undo things I
think that some people think that makes
it quite kind of cold seeming when you
compare it to monogamy that's that's
codependent but it seems to why it's
necessary to function when it's outside
of just one person I think or you or you
know maybe it would be two people all
three of you codependent or sleeping in
the same bed sure but yeah so you never
know it might suit you well like yeah I
definitely when people say could you go
back to being monogamous I kind of think
well I can see a time when maybe there's
only one person in my life and I want to
give a lot of my resource to that person
but I'm never gonna not want to make out
randomly a party and so yeah you know on
holiday I was I was in the States
a few months ago and I was on a
long-distance train and this guide it's
really kind of working-class like Conan
said see this guy just came to start
playing with me and like when I got to
my stop I was like you want to make out
and it was like yeah so we like stood in
the cabin and made out for like 10
minutes
well we I would never be about like it's
funny I went to a what LP I don't know
if you know LP concert she's she's
amazing I suggest looking her up but one
of my friends and this is when I was
rather new to knowing I liked women as
well and well he is queer and definitely
gay like just by looking at her you
can't really tell that she's gay okay
anyway so being there and I was with one
of my friends who it's not in any way
queer but very sexual very and I'm like
how do you flirt she's like go up and
talk to them I was like you're gonna
love that I can't do that like I need to
like no I mean like not need to do that
and yeah connection no that's not
possible
I have to go through being uncomfortable
like yeah alright maybe not gonna happen
I don't know but uh my project in the
world creating the global cooperative
I've had to go through so much being
uncomfortable and putting myself out
there to create this and I can see how
eventually that will spill over into my
romantic life for I'll be like oh you
just make mistakes in the right
direction but there's still so much like
fear there that it it doesn't feel
stress-free and I need it to feel
stress-free and eventually well that
doesn't mean zero like I know there's
like a lot of like the chemistry kind of
comes from the stress but like that
over-over need to look a certain way or
for it to be a certain way or to feel
like I'm not incompetent that area needs
to like fall away a little bit before I
can explore that yeah oh I continue to
feel incompetent especially with women
and more even more and then with men
again you know you know when you're like
oh it's what is it the dunning-kruger
effect where you have a small amount of
knowledge and you think you're an expert
yeah they're like the were like oh god
no so yeah I'm like you're twenty seem
to be all about that cycle and then like
I'm in my 30s now and it's like yep
still yes yes those two are very
intertwined like the dunning-kruger and
sexuality and like masculine
yes um see there's some things going
together like oh but you just having a
female body and being in spaces with
other female people and talking about
those things constantly my whole life
I'm like oh you guys think you're
experts haven't heard a single one of
you actually be experts and whereas like
as a woman wanting to be with a woman
that is already in my head I ain't a
flag every female body is different in
every one like there's a lot of
communication involves and a lot of like
there isn't of one perfect way to be and
yeah it's I'm guessing because I've only
been with them it's easier to be with
men like that's possibly my den in
Kruger days versus not in like well I
think men are very humble with women and
maybe women with men you know cuz
they're like I don't know what the
hell's going on and I know I don't
so here I am I would very much like to
sleep with you so like what do I have to
do to me and in a way well I mean don't
know everyone but those those guys are
dicks but yeah you do get this like you
know what so what's gonna work with you
and I think that the more that the
modern men sleep with you and the more
they're like let's try this let's then
they get ideas it's like this person
like this I'll try it
I'll watch your face okay no I'll try
this I'll try this and yeah I think in a
way yeah there's more knowledge there
because of the humility of course
society supports women and men being
together quite a lot mmm and more of
that that's where I would like to see a
lot more polyamory and asexuality in the
media not sensationalized just in there
there's just normal like you know yeah
yeah Billy has three moms or two dads
and a mom like it's just like yeah that
works without necessarily needed to be
the storyline
yeah like a sexuality even when I was
watching the good doctor and they were
talking to like where he was like no I'm
good like I'm it's not worth it to me to
date after he went on a date that made
him really uncomfortable and
oh they sent him on a date he set
himself up on a date he wanted to go on
a date went on a date it was just like
comfortable and I'm like yeah I
understand that I really understand that
and after I'd like he was like yeah it's
not worth it like it's and and one
doctor like everyone's like no but you
don't understand you got to be in a
relationship it's worth that everyone's
uncomfortable just get in a relationship
and one people is like yeah it's awesome
to be in a relationship but if you don't
need it good on you and I was like kind
of more of what the situation we kind of
is it there isn't a broken or fixed way
to be it's just like everything
especially gender sexuality how much you
want it who you want it with it's all a
spectrum and on are we not spectrum but
like there's nothing wrong about you
because you don't want sex or you don't
want romance or you don't want either or
you want both are you about one with one
gender and one with another because that
women yeah but like that's what that's
more of the diversity we need to tap
into yeah need to make dating sites
around it because none of them are great
for it like I don't even OkCupid which I
haven't been on in years so maybe
they've changed it but like for you even
they're like you can be poly but they
don't even have a way to be poly because
it's like you kind of have to like if
you're a couple looking for a third
person you can't sign up as that that's
not an option like it you don't even
like can't so you have to then sign up
as a male or female or like entity in
order to and it's like that doesn't work
to be able to say this is what I am
which is hard enough and then here's
trap tattoo which is also hard but when
there's no algorithm or no systems
people to find that it's like oh god I
don't want to be set up with a bunch of
like women that I'm gonna have zero
interest in and they're gonna observe
interest in me
yeah like it's a very niche group of
like I'm somewhat androgynous at least
looking
I don't know personality wise when I
come off as and that's what I'm into
that's very easily I don't know how many
other people who Android like wants that
and so it's yeah being someone who's
demisexual and being like I'm not going
through 50 to find a one like that's
just not i barely want to go through two
or three to find one or go through one
to five
you know however that works and so
creating a broader system of being able
to find people and what is it what is
acceptable in society if like there's
nothing broken about that it's just part
of the whole and the world we can honor
our diversity I think the better
relationships go like I think a lot of
monogamous relationships break down
because people aren't allowed to be poly
like people aren't allowed to be right
like you've cheated on every single
person you've been with that's not
ethical poly for sure yeah maybe you're
not meant to be in that relationship
yeah it needs to be an option so we have
about 30 more seconds I'm just gonna go
unlive in about 30 seconds if you wanna
okay chef and I will I will you know do
my ends deal 30-second labels I was
gonna talk about labels
we need them there crap but we need them
is my take you can read my blog to find
out why exactly to that 130 by autistic
modem like I want to go live right on
the second and then end drug it on a
second that's not necessary necessarily
any with the new format that's changed
in the idea cafe if there is a topic
that you want to talk about please
contact me we can set up a time and a
question ones that I'm currently
exploring with other people or
neurodiversity mental health donor
conception commuter I'd like I've
reached out to all the communities I'm a
part of like who wants to pick a
question and do it what we're doing yeah
and so if you want to be involved in one
of them you can either contact me pick
me set one up ourselves or you can join
the Facebook group so that every time
I've set one up with one person I'm
gonna post it in there so that I'll be
likes Thursday at 2:00 p.m. Pacific
Standard Time we're talking about mental
health and here's the question right so
it'll be a diverse group of people
because I'm a diverse group of people
and then we did a bye everybody never
know how to like actually end it